<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.9.1" xml:lang="en-US">
  <compounddef id="indexpage" kind="page">
    <compoundname>index</compoundname>
    <title>Pyedit Pro</title>
    <briefdescription>
    </briefdescription>
    <detaileddescription>
<sect2 id="index_1autotoc_md0">
<title>Welcome to PyEdPro.</title>
<para>This is modern multi-platform editor. Simple, powerful, configurable, extendable. Goodies like macro recording / playback, spell check, column select, multiple clipboards, unlimited undo ... makes it an editor that I use every day.</para>
<para>This is an open source text editor. Written in python. The motivation for this project was to create a modern multi-platform editor. Simple, powerful, configurable, extendable. To run this module without installation put the supporting files in the &apos;pedlib&apos; subdirectory under the main file&apos;s direcory.</para>
<para>(like &apos;cp -a * to_target&apos;)</para>
<para>This project is a successor of pyedit, after porting it to GTK3. PyEdPro will run anywhere PyGObject can run.</para>
<para>Working and tested platforms currently are: <verbatim>  Win 7 .. Win 10 ...
  Centos 6 .. 7 Ubuntu 14 ... 16 ...  20.x (should run on any linux )
  Windows (Native) plus MSYS2, Mingw,
  Raspberry PI 3, Raspberry PI 4, ...
  Mac ** Some functions are disabled - in particular async processing
</verbatim> I mainly run it on Ubuntu, and in Win32 / MSYS2, some Fedora, Windows 10, and the Raspberry-Pi. It behaves consistently on all these platforms, it is an absolute joy to edit in a different platform without the learning curve of new keystrokes. If you want an editor that works the same way in all your workspaces, PyEdPro is the one.</para>
<para>Pyedpro functions near identical on Linux / Windows / Mac / Raspberry PI</para>
<para>Pyedpro has: <verbatim>       o  macro recording/play,
       o  search/replace,
       o  functional navigation,
       o  comment/string spell check,
       o  full spell check, spell suggestion dialog
       o  auto backup,
       o  persistent undo/redo,  (undo beyond last save)
       o  auto complete, auto correct,
       o
       o  ... and a lot more.
</verbatim> It is fast, it is extendable. The editor has a table driven key mapping. One can easily edit the key map in keyhand.py, and the key actions in acthand.py The default key map resembles gedit / wed / etp / brief</para>
<para>ASCII text editor, requires pyGtk. (pygobject) See pygtk-dependencies for easy install of dependencies. See also the INSTALL file. </para>
</sect2>
    </detaileddescription>
    <location file="pyedpro/build/scripts-3.10/pyedpro.py"/>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
